Guide to the the Stuart Wright Bibliographic Collection of George Garrett, 1951-1993 RL.00436
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Stuart Wright Bibliographic Collection of George Garrett
1951-1993 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Wright, Stuart T.
RL.00436
20 Linear Feet
Stuart Wright (1948-), an author, bibliographer, and publisher, attended Roxboro (N.C.) High School and Wake Forest University, where he received B.A. degrees in German and Music. He received his master's degree in Southern Studies in 1973 and a second master's degree in U.S. History in 1980, both from Wake Forest University. In the late 1970s and through much of the 1980s, Wright served as Lecturer in Education at Wake Forest. The collection consists of materials related to the Virginia writer George Garrett (1929-2008) assembled by author, bibliographer, and publisher Stuart Wright. Wright published George Garrett: a bibliography, 1947-1988 / edited by Stuart Wright. Huntsville, TX: Texas Review Press, Sam Houston State University, 1989.
About 1080 items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Stuart Wright Bibliographic Collection of George Garrett was received as a gift in 1993 from Stuart Wright.
Biographical Note
Stuart Wright (1948-) attended Roxboro (N.C.) High School and Wake Forest University, where he received B.A. degrees in German and Music. He received his master's degree in Southern Studies in 1973 and a second master's degree in U.S. History in 1980, both from Wake Forest University. In the late 1970s and through much of the 1980s, Wright served as Lecturer in Education at Wake Forest.
Since 1977 Wright has published, in the form of broadsides and limited editions, poetry and essays by A. R. Ammons, Fred Chappell, James Dickey, William Goyen, George Garrett, and Eudora Welty, among others. He also compiled bibliographies of several writers, including Andrew Lytle, Donald Davies, Reynolds Price, Robert Morgan, Dickey, and Ammons. He also edited The Conference Letters of Benjamin H. Freeman and The Recollections of A. D. Reynolds. With F. D. Bridgewater, he translated The Great Cavalry Battle of Brandy Station by Heres von Borcke and Justus Scheibert. Wright was a member of the Grolier Club from 1980 to 1998, when he moved to England.
Description taken from the finding aid to the Stuart T. Wright Papers, 1977-1986, at the Southern Historical Collection, UNC-Chapel Hill, and the Stuart Wright Collection at Joyner Library, East Carolina University.
Collection Overview
A Collection of materials related to the Virginia writer George Garrett (1929-2008) assembled by author, bibliographer, and publisher Stuart Wright. Wright later published George Garrett: a bibliography, 1947-1988 / edited by Stuart Wright. Huntsville, TX: Texas Review Press, Sam Houston State University, 1989.
The collection consists chiefly of serials containing writings by Garrett, including poetry, short stories, literary criticism, reviews, editorials, screenplays, dramatic scripts, novels, and a few speeches. Many of the items are inscribed or signed by George Garrett and other authors. There are also manuscripts of Garrett's screenplays and other writings. Many of Garrett's literary criticism pieces concern the writings of William Faulkner.
Other formats include photographs including publicity photos for the movie The young lovers, screenplay by Garrett. Biographical data on Garrett is found in interviews, clippings, and biographical sketches of Garrett's career as a writer and teacher. Other periodicals containing the writings of other writers of interest to Garrett are included in this collection.
Arrangement note
Collection is arranged in chronological order and in title order.
Related Material
George P. Garrett Papers, 1929-2008
Rubenstein Library, Duke University
Motion picture plays; American poetry -- 20th century; Short stories, American -- 20th century; American literature -- 20th century -- Periodicals; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Interviews; Provenance -- Wright, Stuart T.; Garrett, George, 1929-2008; Garrett, George, 1929-2008 -- Bibliography; Faulkner, William, 1897-1962; Wright, Stuart T.
- Writings and Speeches, 1951-1993 and undated
  Scope and Contents note
  Published works by George Garrett, including articles, fiction, poetry, reviews, and a few speeches. Some items included here are volumes edited by Garrett with no writings by him contained in them; these are marked with the abbreviation ed. Arranged in chronological order by title of periodical or article from most specific date to more general date (e.g., 1981, Dec. 15 appears before Winter, 1981). Biographical information on Garrett written by others can be found in the Biographical Data Series.
  - Writings and Speeches, 1951-1959
    - Nassau Literary Magazine, Casual Marginalia, A Note on Creon, Summer Abstraction, 1951, Nov. (Box 1)
    - A Ten Year Record, Princeton University, biographical sketch (written by Garrett), 1952 (Box 1)
    - The Carolina Quarterly, Vaudeville Suite, 1955, Fall (Box 1)
    - College English, Swift, 1956, Jan. (Box 1)
    - Epos, Episode in Emerson's Garden, 1956, Winter (Box 1)
    - Four Quarters, The Other Side of the Coin, 1957, Jan. (Box 1)
    - College English, Congreve, 1957, Feb. (Box 1)
    - Four Quarters, Pastoral, 1957, May (Box 1)
    - The Princeton University Library Chronicle, An Examination of the Poetry of William Faulkner, 1957, Spring (Box 1)
    - The Sewanee Review, Fragment of a Tragedy, The Quest, Alice Cutting Flowers, and The Sleeping Gypsy, 1957, Spring (Box 1)
    - Approach, Riddle Man, 1957, Summer (Box 1)
    - Folio A Hard Row to Hoe, 1957, Summer (Box 1)
    - The Georgia Review, Harry S. Edwards: Eneas Africanus, 1957, Summer (Box 1)
    - Approach, The Rare Unicorn, 1957, Fall (Box 1)
    - New Poems by American Poets, 1957 (2 editions, paper and hardback) (Box 1)
    - Poets of Today IV, The Reverend Ghost, 1957 (Box 1)
    - College English, Matthew Arnold and Snapshot, 1958, Mar. (Box 1)
    - Approach, Transition, 1958, Spring (Box 1)
    - The Georgia Review, Promises: Poems, 1954-1956 By Robert Penn Warren. (review) (Box 1)
    - 1958, Spring (Box 1)
    - Some Revisions in As I Lay Dying, 1958, June (reprint) (Box 1)
    - Compass Review, Harangue by a Clown in Plaincothes, Valerie Bettis: Streetcar 1958, Summer (Box 1)
    - Approach, The Magi: A Short Story, 1958, Fall (Box 1)
    - Coastlines, Bathing Beauty, 1958, Autumn (Box 1)
    - The Georgia Review, Owen Wister Out West: His Journals and Letters 1958, Fall (Box 1)
    - Prairie Schooner, The Earliest Faulkner, 1958, Fall (Box 1)
    - The Virginia Quarterly Review, Bread from Stones, 1958, Autumn (Box 1)
    - Critique, By Love Possessed: The Pattern and the Hero, 1958, Winter (Box 1)
    - The Sewanee Review, Narcissus and Buzzard, 1958, Winter (Box 1)
    - Prairie Schooner, Come as You Are, 1958-1959, Winter (Box 1)
    - Abraham's Knife and Other Poems, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Epos Anthology, Episode in Emerson's Garden, 1958 (Box 1)
    - The Sleeping Gypsy and Other Poems, 1958 (Box 1)
    - New Work by 5 Poets, Fat Man, Abraham's Knife, Ballad, Old Lecher, Revival, Are You Saved???, Young Man, 1959, 11 Apr. (Box 1)
    - The Function of the Pasiphae Myth in Brother to Dragons, 1959, April (reprint) (Box 1)
    - Mademoiselle, An Evening Performance, 1959, April (Box 1)
    - A Reading of New Poems, Bubbles, Come As You Are, Gleeman, Solitaire, 1959, 6 May (Box 1)
    - Accent, Holy Roller, 1959, Spring (Box 1)
    - Approach, The Only Dragon on the Road, 1959, Spring (Box 1)
    - The Georgia Review, The Confidence Man, 1959, Spring (Box 1)
    - The Sewanee Review, Fat Man, A Toast for the Bride and the Groom, and (Box 1)
    - Figure Study, 1959, Spring (Box 1)
    - Texas Studies in Literature and Language, Faulkner's Early Literary Criticism, 1959, Spring (Box 1)
    - Faulkner's Early Literary Criticism, 1959, Spring (reprint) (Box 1)
    - Approach, The Mower and The Echo, 1959, Summer (Box 1)
    - Transatlantic Review, For My Sons, Nocturne 2, 3 Fabliaux, 1959, Summer (ed.) (Box 1)
    - Botteghe Oscure, The Moth, 1959, Autumn (Box 1)
  - Writings and Speeches, 1959-1962
    - The Literary Review, King, 1959-1960, Winter (Box 2)
    - Transatlantic Review, 1959-1960, Winter (ed.) (Box 2)
    - The Finished Man, 1959 (Box 2)
    - The Wesleyan University Alumnus, Fat Man, 1960, Feb. (Box 2)
    - Salvatore Quasimodo, Garrett's translation of Dead of Winter, At the Statue of Illaria del Carretto, and Man of the Hour, 1960, 8 May (Box 2)
    - Spring Poetry Festival at Wesleyan, Rape of the Sabines, 1960, Spring (Box 2)
    - Poetry Northwest, Crows at Paestum, 1960, Spring/Summer (Box 2)
    - Approach, Tongue-tied. 1960, Summer (Box 2)
    - The Georgia Review, review: William Faulkner: New Orleans Sketches, 1960, Summer (Box 2)
    - Poetry, Circe, 1960, Summer (Box 2)
    - The Sewanee Review, Good-bye, Old Paint, I'm Leaving Cheyenne and Abraham's Knife, 1960, Autumn (Box 2)
    - The Transatlantic Review, A Game of Catch, 1960, Dec. (Box 2)
    - Shenandoah, Love's a Cold Kingdom, 1960, Winter (Box 2)
    - The Best American Short Stories, An Evening Performance, 1960(2 editions, paper and hardcover) (Box 2)
    - The Sewanee Review, The Old Army Game, 1961, Summer (Box 2)
    - A Wreath for Garibaldi, 1961, Summer (reprint) (Box 2)
    - The Kenyon Review, A Wreath for Garibaldi, 1961, Summer (Box 2)
    - The Transatlantic Review, Irony, 1961, Fall (Box 2)
    - Approach, New Song and Three Morning Creatures, 1961, Winter (Box 2)
    - Transatlantic Review, 1961, Winter (ed.) (Box 2)
    - A Reading of New Poems, 1961 (2 copies) (Box 2)
    - Which Ones are the Enemy?, 1961 (paperback) (Box 2)
    - Janus, Five Translations, (Justice, Goat, One by Catullus, Plow, Martial's First Epigram) 1962, Spring (Box 2)
    - The Sewanee Review, More Geese Than Swans Now Live, 1962, Spring (Box 2)
    - The Literary Review, Rainy Day and Postcard, 1962, Summer (Box 2)
    - The Virginia Quarterly Review, Sweeter than the Flesh of Birds, 1962, Autumn (Box 2)
    - The Best American Short Stories 1962, The Old Army Game, 1962(2 editions, paper and hardcover) (Box 2)
    - Sir Slob and the Princess: A Play for Children, 1962 (Box 2)
    - Southern Poetry Today, For a Bitter Season and Plow, 1962 (2 copies) (Box 2)
  - Writings and Speeches, 1963-1965
    - Swank, What's the Matter With Mary Jane, 1963, July (2 copies) (Box 3)
    - Modern Fiction Studies, The Major Poetry of Joyce Cary, 1963, Autumn (Box 3)
    - The Princeton University Library Chronicle, Seven Princeton Poets, Salome, 1963, Autumn (2 editions, paper and hardcover) (Box 3)
    - Shenandoah, The Last of the Buffalo Hunters, 1963, Winter (Box 3)
    - New Writing from Virginia, preface by Garrett, 1963(2 copies) (Box 3)
    - One Kind of Anarchy and Two Pedagogical Poems, 1963 (Box 3)
    - The Princeton Alumni Weekly, Manifesto, 1964, 21 Jan. (Box 3)
    - Author's Guild Bulletin, The Winter in the University, 1964, April (Box 3)
    - The Hollins Critic, John Cheever, 1964, April (Box 3)
    - The Virginia Quarterly Review, The Naked Voice, 1964, Spring (Box 3)
    - University: A Princeton Magazine, Salome, 1964, Fall (Box 3)
    - The Georgia Review, The Influence of William Faulkner, 1964, Winter (Box 3)
    - The Influence of William Faulkner, 1964, Winter (reprint) (Box 3)
    - Shenandoah, My Pretty Birdie, Pretty Birdie in My Cage, 1964, Winter (Box 3)
    - Cold Ground was My Bed Last Night, 1964 (Box 3)
    - The Princeton Alumni Weekly, 1965, 23 Feb. (Box 3)
    - The Hollins Critic, Saul Bellow, 1965, April (Box 3)
    - Queen, Bread from Stones, 1965, 16 June (Box 3)
    - Logos: A Christian Review for University Students, A Comparison, 1965, Dec. (Box 3)
    - University of Virginia Alumni News, The Kandy-Kolored Playboy-Flake Streamline Faerie Queene, or A Portrait of the Writer as a University Student, 1965, Dec. (Box 3)
    - American Poetry, Against the Grain: Poets Writing Today, 1965 (Box 3)
    - Chicago Review, Two Recent Volumes, 1965 (review, poetry of Miller Williams and David R. Slavitt) (Box 3)
    - Do, Lord, Remember Me, 1965(2 editions, paper and hardcover) (Box 3)
    - Fifty Best American Short Stories-1915-1965, The Old Army Game, 1965(2 copies) (Box 3)
    - Red Clay Reader II, To Whom Shall I Call Now In My Hour Of Need? 1965(2 copies) (Box 3)
  - Writings and Speeches, 1966-1971
    - The Hollins Critic, Truman Capote, 1966, Feb. (Box 4)
    - Shenandoah, A New Look At William Faulkner, 1966, Spring (Box 4)
    - Transatlantic Review, 1966, Summer (ed.) (Box 4)
    - Transatlantic Review, Excursion, 1966, Autumn (ed.) (Box 4)
    - Dialogue pasted on back of newspaper (probably a stage prop), unknown play, 1966 (Box 4)
    - Rapier, Exemplary Letters From the Realm of Gold, 1967, January (Box 4)
    - Harvest, Two Poems, 1967, May (Box 4)
    - Plume and Sword, Three Poems on One Theme, 1967, Spring (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, Wright Morris, 1967, June (Box 4)
    - Latitudes, Two Exemplary Letters, 1967, Summer (Box 4)
    - Per/Se, Poison Pen, 1967, Summer (Box 4)
    - Transatlantic Review, 1967, Summer (ed.) (Box 4)
    - For A Bitter Season, 1967 (Box 4)
    - Toward Winter, An Open Letter From George Garrett, 1968, Jan. (2 copies) (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, Norman Podhoretz, 1968, Feb. (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, William Merwin, 1968, June (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, ed., 1968, Dec. (Box 4)
    - Latitudes, Two Poems, 1968, Winter (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, 1969, Feb. (ed.) (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, 1969, April (ed.) (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, 1969, June (ed.) (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, William Harrison, 1969, October (Box 4)
    - Hollins College Bulletin, Here Today, Gone Tomorrow, 1969, November (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, 1969, December, (ed.) (Box 4)
    - The Kenyon Review 126, 'The International Symposium on the Short Story, Part Three, 1969(2 copies) (Box 4)
    - Mill Mountain Review, Poison Pen, 1969 (Box 4)
    - Lycoming Review, Tea with Expatriates, 1969-1970 (2 copies) (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, 1970, Feb. (ed.) (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, 1970, April (ed.) (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, 1970, June (ed.) (Box 4)
    - Contempora, The Final Tape of Doctor Wisdom, 1970, July/August (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, 1970, Oct. (ed.) (Box 4)
    - Contempora, How Far Can You Go: An Interview With Fred Wiseman, 1970, Oct./Nov. (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, 1970, Dec. (ed.) (Box 4)
    - Dreaming with Adam: Notes on an Imaginary History, 1970 (reprint) (Box 4)
    - Fly By Night, Jane Amor, Space Nurse, 1970 (Box 4)
    - Stories from The Transatlantic Review, A Game of Catch, 1970 (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, 1971, Feb. (ed.) (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, 1971, April (ed.) (Box 4)
    - The Film Journal, 1971, Spring (ed.) (Box 4)
    - The Georgia Review, Sebastian in the Looking Glass, 1971, Spring (Box 4)
    - Hollins College, Examination Book, Cargoes, 1971, Spring (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, 1971, June (ed.) (Box 4)
    - The Hollins Critic, 1971, Aug. (ed.) (Box 4)
    - Mississippi Quarterly, Talking with Shelby Foote, 1971, Fall (Box 4)
    - Metro Hampton Roads Magazine, George Garrett: A Personal Look at the Fox, 1971, Dec.-Jan. (Box 4)
    - The Southern Review, The Apple Tree, 1971, Winter (Box 4)
    - 'The Apple Tree': An Excerpt from Death of the Fox, 1971 (reprint) (Box 4)
    - Death of the Fox, 1971(2 copies, hardcover) (Box 4)
    - Death of the Fox, 1971 (paperback) (Box 4)
    - Mill Mountain Review, In Appreciation of George Garrett, 1971(2 copies) (Box 4)
    - Mill Mountain Review, An Excerpt from The Death of the Fox, 1971(2 copies) (Box 4)
    - Suggestions for Instructors to Accompany Film Scripts One and Film Scripts Two, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Writings and Speeches, 1972-1976
    - American Libraries, The South, 1972, Jan. (2 copies) (Box 5)
    - The South Carolina Review, Review of Little Chicago Suite, 1972, June (Box 5)
    - The American Scholar, The Revolving Bookstand (book reviews), 1972, Summer (Box 5)
    - Writer's Digest, Exclusive Interview with George Garrett, 1972, Nov. (Box 5)
    - Contempora, Forms of the Public Novel, 1972, Sept./Feb. (Box 5)
    - Contempora, Thank You For a Real Nice Time, You Play it Dead Straight, 1972, Mar./July (Box 5)
    - Contempora, Horror Film as Metaphysical Fable, 1972, Aug./Dec. (Box 5)
    - The Georgia Review, Grace is Most of It, 1972, Winter (Box 5)
    - Craft so Hard to Learn, 1972(ed.) (Box 5)
    - The Film Journal, 1972(ed.) (Box 5)
    - Toward Winter, Buzzard, 1972 (Box 5)
    - Worksheet, 1972(ed.) (Box 5)
    - Contempora, 1973, Jan./April (ed.) (Box 5)
    - Movies and Sexuality, How Do You Like Your Hero?: Over Easy or Sunny-side Up?, 1973, May/June (Box 5)
    - Gone Soft, Here Comes the Bride, 1973, Spring (Box 5)
    - The Hollins Critic, On Young Writers and New Writing, 1973, Aug. (Box 5)
    - The Film Journal, 1973(ed.) (Box 5)
    - The Magic Striptease, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Hemispheres, Carnival Poem, 1974, July (Box 5)
    - Foote's The Civil War: A Version for Posterity 1974-75, Winter (reprint) (Box 5)
    - Mississippi Quarterly, Foote's The Civil War: A Version for Posterity, 1974-1975, Winter (Box 5)
    - The Nassau Literary Review, Live Now and Pay Later..., 1974, Winter (Box 5)
    - The Film Journal, 1974(ed.) (Box 5)
    - Intro 5, 1974(ed.) (Box 5)
    - Intro 6, 1974(ed.) (Box 5)
    - Ploughshares, review of Looking for Fred Schmit, 1974(2 copies) (Box 5)
    - Anthology of Epos Poets, Familiar Riddle, 1975, Spring/Summer (Box 5)
    - Francis Marion Review, At Least They'll Have Candlelight, 1975 (Box 5)
    - Intro 7, 1975(ed.) (Box 5)
  - Writings and Speeches, 1976-1980
    - Sandlapper, This Place, This State, This South Carolina, 1976, Jan. (Box 6)
    - Sandlapper, Little Tune for a Steel String Guitar, 1976, Mar. (Box 6)
    - Letters, A Toast to all the Poets, 1976, July (Box 6)
    - The Sewanee Review, The Literature of the Great War, 1976, Summer (Box 6)
    - Sandlapper, The Long and the Short of It, 1976, Oct. (Box 6)
    - The South Carolina Review, David Tillinghast, 1976, Nov. (Box 6)
    - Francis Marion Review, Envoy, 1976 (Box 6)
    - The Nassau Literary Magazine, Some Things Beautiful and Indifferent, and Summer Abstraction, 1976 (Box 6)
    - Willow Springs Magazine, Picture of a Horseman Riding North, 1977, Dec. (Box 6)
    - Into the Round Air, Dancing Class and Apology, 1977 (Box 6)
    - Intro 8, The Liar's Craft, 1977 (Box 6)
    - Jeopardy, Book Review, Jacob, and The Messenger, 1977 (Box 6)
    - Review La Booche, Luck's Shining Child, and On Death and December, 1977(2 copies) (Box 6)
    - Southern Poetry, York Harbor Morning, 1977 (Box 6)
    - The Texas Arts Journal, P.S. What is Octagon Soup?, 1977 (2 copies, one of which is limited edition, 22 copies printed, in hard slipcase with several signed literary mss. by other poets in folder) (Box 6)
    - Transatlantic Review, Garrett interviewed by Allen Wier, 1977 (Box 6)
    - Vanderbilt Poetry Review, Little Transformation, 1977 (Box 6)
    - Windfall Poems, 1977 (Box 6)
    - New Mexico Humanities Review, All That the Dark Sentinel Could Wager: An Excerpt From the Novel Elizabeth and James, 1978, Jan. (Box 6)
    - The Puckerbrush Review, 1978, Spring (ed.) (Box 6)
    - The Sewanee Review Coming Out of Left Field, 1978, Summer (Box 6)
    - Lowlands Review, Only as a Pilgrim, 1978, Fall (Box 6)
    - New Virginia Review, Flash Cards: Splitting Wood, Our Little Secret, Late Night Rain, Medicine Show, 1978/79 (Box 6)
    - Willow Springs Magazine, Mundane Metamorphosis, 1978/79, Winter (Box 6)
    - The Blue Ridge Review, An Invitation to Dance, 1978 (Box 6)
    - Intro 9, Close to Home, 1978 (Box 6)
    - Review La Booche, Message Sent in the Clear, A Light Rain, My Main Confessional Poem, Rival Poet, To a Certain Critic, 1978 (Box 6)
    - Bennington Review, Weathers of Remembering, 1979, Apr. (Box 6)
    - Kudzu, Pathetic Fallacy/Gray on Gray, 1979, Spring (Box 6)
    - AWP Newsletter, The Latest Development in the Saga of Intro 9: A New Kind of Soap Opera, 1977, Dec. and Letter to the Editor, 1979, Sept. (Box 6)
    - The Bellingham Review, 1979, Fall (Box 6)
    - To Recollect A Cloud of Ghosts, 1979, Christmas (Box 6)
    - Blue Buildings, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Contemporary Southern Poetry, An Anthology, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Contemporary Literary Scene II (introduction by Garrett), 1979 (Box 6)
    - Hard Scuffle, A Man Who Casts No Shadow, 1979 (Box 6)
    - The Sewanee Review, Technics and Pyrotechnics, 1980, Summer (2 copies) (Box 6)
    - The Texas Review, These Fooleries Will Please Thee Less, 1980, Fall (Box 6)
  - Writings and Speeches, 1981-1984
    - Kansas Quarterly, Statement on the Fiction Awards, 1981, Winter (Box 7)
    - The Agni Review, Riding from Darkness into Light, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Enchanted Ground, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Luck's Shining Child, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Riverfronts, The Rivals, 1981 (Box 7)
    - R.V. Cassill, Promissory Note, 1981 (Box 7)
    - The North American Review, Communiqué from the Academy of Projectors, 1982, Mar. (Box 7)
    - The Bellingham Review, excerpt from Elizabeth and James, 1982, Spring (2 copies) (Box 7)
    - The Texas Review, Soldiers, 1982, Spring (Box 7)
    - The Missouri Review, excerpt from Elizabeth and James, 1982, Summer (Box 7)
    - Black Warrior Review, excerpt from Elizabeth and James, 1982, Fall (Box 7)
    - The Georgia Review, How an Ape in Purple Met Jock of the Park, 1982, Fall (2 copies) (Box 7)
    - Tri-Quarterly, 1982 Fall (ed.) (Box 7)
    - Literary Magazine Review, review: Ploughshares, 1982, Winter (Box 7)
    - Chelsea, Meeting in the Tiring Room, (excerpt from Elizabeth and James ), 1982 (Box 7)
    - The Girl in the Black Raincoat, 1982 (Garrett wrote preface to collection of stories) (Box 7)
    - The Teller and the Tale: Aspects of the Short Story, Plain/or Fancy: Where the Short Story Is and May Be Going, 1982(2 copies) (Box 7)
    - Three Rivers Poetry Journal, This Business of Getting the World Right: The Poetry of Brendan Galvin (review), 1982 (Box 7)
    - The South Carolina Review, excerpt from Elizabeth and James: A Letter that Will Never Be Written, 1983, Spring (Box 7)
    - The Virginia Quarterly Review, Laughter in the Dark and Other Things, 1983, Spring (Box 7)
    - The Texas Review, excerpts from Elizabeth and James: Courtier: It is the Wine Talking, The Hunter's Joy, 1983, Spring/Summer (Box 7)
    - The Sewanee Review, American Short Fiction and the Literary Marketplace, 1983, Winter (Box 7)
    - The Crescent Review, excerpt from Elizabeth and James: Confirmation, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Fire Among the Thorns, excerpt from Elizabeth and James, 1983(3 copies, privately printed) (Box 7)
    - The Sounding Brass, excerpt from Elizabeth and James: The Queen's Pigmy and The Magic Mirror, 1983 (Box 7)
    - The Succession: A Novel of Elizabeth and James, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Mississippi Quarterly, A Few Things about Fred Chappell, 1983-1984, Winter (Box 7)
    - Bennington Review, In the Absence of a Manifesto, 1984, Spring (Box 7)
    - The Texas Review, 1984, Spring/Summer (guest fiction editor) (Box 7)
    - The Collected Poems of George Garrett, 1984 (Box 7)